<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-11-13T23:40:41+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">rathikashi.github.io</title><entry><title type="html">Interesting Puzzles</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/13/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Interesting Puzzles" /><published>2020-11-13T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-11-13T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2020/11/13/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2020/11/13/first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello world&lt;/strong&gt;, these are some fun problems I have come across!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s horse racing time again and this year there’s a line-up of 25 horses. You can run a maximum of five horses per race. How many races do you need to find the fastest 3? (You can assume that the fastest horse always wins a race).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A scientist gathered four math students. They were then lined up so that each one could see the one in front of them but not behind them. Each had a hat placed on their head. So the student in the back could see the hats of the three students in front, but the student in front could not see any hats.
 “There is a red hat, a white hat, a blue hat, and a hat that is a duplicate of one of those colors,” the scientist said.
Starting with the one in the back, each student was asked what color hat they were wearing. They all gave the correct answer! What was the arrangement of the hats that made this possible?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Imagine there are a 100 people in line to board a plane that seats 100. The first person in line realizes he lost his boarding pass so when he boards he decides to take a random seat instead. Every person that boards the plane after him will either take their “proper” seat, or if that seat is taken, a random seat instead. What is the probability that the last person that boards will end up in his/her proper seat.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Hello world, these are some fun problems I have come across!</summary></entry></feed>